<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-27T22:00:25+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</id><title type="html">Technical Blog</title><subtitle>A blog from Damian Flynn, a Microsoft MVP and Cisco Champion</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building a better blog; an experiment in UI and UX</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/building-a-better-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a better blog; an experiment in UI and UX" /><published>2017-06-25T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-25T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/building-a-better-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/building-a-better-blog/">My initial blog had some nice features, but really didn't do anything to place my content first. Was it really important that my logo be prominently placed? Not really, I am recoding both technical, and product related tips, tricks and news, and not focusing on how to keep a Wordpress site secure, and more importantly working reliably, So I have chosen to leverage static site technology, and ensure the layout focuses on what is truly important, the content.

## The article should have your sole attention

![the new content-focused blog](/images/posts/2017-06-25/old-blog-screenshot.png){: .img-fluid .border }

The hamburger menu - gone. If you're visiting on mobile, chances are you got here from a link, which means you're interested in the article. As you move down the article, it's just content.

Some of the other standards have worked their way in - how long will it take to read, and how fresh is the content?

If you're visiting on a tablet or larger, you start to see another layer of content/navigation. The 10 most recent article appear as a sidebar. We still want your attention on the article, so content other than a headline is blurred until you hover.

## How do I move around?

Once you reach the end of the article, you're presented with related articles (if we can find any based on tags), else you're given the previous and next articles for additional reading. You can also explore  content by tags, author, or click the binoculars to bring all articles into focus.

Curious about who we are? As you move back up the article, a footer with light navigation appears. We just keep it out of your way while you're reading.

## What's next?

I am planning other features, including posting events; and looking for feedback? What do you think?</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="UI" /><category term="UX" /><summary type="html">My initial blog had some nice features, but really didn’t do anything to place my content first. Was it really important that my logo be prominently placed? Not really, I am recoding both technical, and product related tips, tricks and news, and not focusing on how to keep a Wordpress site secure, and more importantly working reliably, So I have chosen to leverage static site technology, and ensure the layout focuses on what is truly important, the content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adding Mermaid support to the site</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/adding-mermaids-back-in-the-game/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adding Mermaid support to the site" /><published>2017-06-23T15:25:51+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-23T15:25:51+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/adding-mermaids-back-in-the-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/adding-mermaids-back-in-the-game/">&lt;p&gt;A picture is worth a thousand words, so I assume a diagram is worth a &lt;strong&gt;billion&lt;/strong&gt; words. Expressing our ideas is important and our blog is an outlet to not only share with our teammates, but the broader community of readers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://knsv.github.io/mermaid/&quot;&gt;Mermaid&lt;/a&gt; is a simple markdown based diagramming language with a compelling result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Placing the following html in our posts…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-html highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;mermaid&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
graph TD;
    A--&amp;gt;B;
    A--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;D;
    C--&amp;gt;D;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;results in the wonderful diagram below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mermaid&quot; style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
graph TD;
    A--&amp;gt;B;
    A--&amp;gt;C;
    B--&amp;gt;D;
    C--&amp;gt;D;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I can create diagrams like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;mermaid&quot;&gt;
sequenceDiagram
    participant Alice
    participant Bob
    Alice-&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
    loop Healthcheck
        John-&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
    end
    Note right of John: Rational thoughts prevail...
    John--&amp;gt;Alice: Great!
    John-&amp;gt;Bob: How about you?
    Bob--&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html">A picture is worth a thousand words, so I assume a diagram is worth a billion words. Expressing our ideas is important and our blog is an outlet to not only share with our teammates, but the broader community of readers. Mermaid is a simple markdown based diagramming language with a compelling result. Placing the following html in our posts… &amp;lt;div class=&quot;mermaid&quot;&amp;gt; graph TD; A--&amp;gt;B; A--&amp;gt;C; B--&amp;gt;D; C--&amp;gt;D; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; results in the wonderful diagram below. graph TD; A--&amp;gt;B; A--&amp;gt;C; B--&amp;gt;D; C--&amp;gt;D; Additionally, I can create diagrams like this. sequenceDiagram participant Alice participant Bob Alice-&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you? loop Healthcheck John-&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria end Note right of John: Rational thoughts prevail... John--&amp;gt;Alice: Great! John-&amp;gt;Bob: How about you? Bob--&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2127/2067252947_fcaa9ca286_z_d.jpg?zz=1" /></entry></feed>